Preliminary Guide to the Rotary International. District 7710 Records, 1920-2013 RL.01114
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rotary International. District 7710 records
1920-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rotary International
RL.01114
26.1 Linear Feet
Rotary International was established as a men's service organization in Chicago in 1905. This collection contains records relating to Rotary International, District 7710, which includes counties in central North Carolina. Includes the district's conference programs, conference minutes, executive committee minutes, correspondence, directories, policies and procedures. Also includes information about the district's exchange program and various club histories, including numerous club rosters and club bulletins for the Chapel Hill and Raleigh Rotary Clubs. There are also clippings, newsletters, photographs, and slides related to the organization's activities.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
Gift, 2008 (2008-0278), 13.5 linear ft.
Gift, 2009 (2009-0225), 0.2 linear ft.
Gift, 2010 (2010-0145), 0.6 linear ft.
Gift, date unknown (2012-0078), 2.0 lin. ft.
Gift, 2013 (2013-0060), 7.5 lin. ft.
Gift, 2015 (2015-0145).
Historical Note
Men's service organization established in Chicago in 1905.
Collection Overview
Records relating to Rotary International, District 7710, which includes counties in North Carolina. Includes the district's conference programs, conference minutes, executive committee minutes, correspondence, directories, policies and procedures. Also includes information about the district's exchange program and various club histories, including numerous club rosters and club bulletins for the Chapel Hill and Raleigh Rotary Clubs. There are also clippings, newsletters, photographs, and slides related to the organization's activities.
The addition (2004-0126) (1000 items, 3.0 lin. ft.; dated [1960s]-[1980s]) consists of manuals, directories, correspondence, convention information, programs, and brochures related to District 7710.
The addition (2008-0278) (10800 items; 12 lin. ft.; 1999-2008) includes administrative and program files, conference manuals, and other materials relating to Rotary International's activities between 1999 and 2008.
The addition (2009-0225) (450 items, 0.2 lin ft.; dated 2003-2005) includes materials related to district simplified grants.
The addition (2010-0145) (450 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; 2005-2008) includes binders with District Simplified Grant material, as well as materials from the district's committees and activities.
The addition (2013-0060) ( 7.5 lin. ft.; 1984-2012) includes correspondence, administrative and program files, conference and training manuals, directories, audiovisual materials, and other materials relating to Rotary International's activities between 1984 and 2012.
The addition (2015-0145) ( 1.5 lin. ft.; 2003-2004) includes correspondence, administrative and program files, conference and training manuals, electronic records, and other materials relating to Rotary International's activities in 2003-2004. The bulk of the material relates to Mike Thacker's activities as District General (D-7710).
Related Materials
The David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library also holds the Rotary Club of Durham records.
Clubs -- North Carolina; Clubs -- United States; Volunteers -- North Carolina; Rotary Club (Raleigh, N.C.) -- History; Rotary Club (Chapel Hill, N.C.) -- History; Rotary Club of Durham (Durham, N.C.)
- Accession (2004-0126), 1960s-1980s, 5 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The addition (2004-0126) (1000 items, 3.0 lin. ft.; dated [1960s]-[1980s]) consists of manuals, directories, correspondence, convention information, programs, and brochures related to District 7710.
- Accession (2008-0278), 1999-2008, 8 boxes
  The addition (2008-0278) (10800 items; 12 lin. ft.; 1999-2008) includes administrative and program files, conference manuals, and other materials relating to Rotary International's activities between 1999 and 2008.
  - Charlie Hatch, 2004-2005
    - District Council (Box 1)
    - GSE (Box 1)
    - Scholars (Box 1)
    - The Rotary Foundation (Box 1)
    - RYLA (Box 1)
    - Interact/Rotaract (Box 1)
    - Friendship Exchange (Box 1)
    - District Conference (Box 1)
    - District Assemblies (Box 1)
    - PETS (Box 1)
    - College of Governors (Box 1)
    - District News Letters/correspondence (Box 1)
    - Rotary Youth Exchange (Box 1)
    - District Awards (Box 1)
    - CART (Box 1)
    - Boys and Girls Home (Box 1)
    - Centennial Year Activities (Box 1)
    - 4-Way Test Contest (Box 1)
    - Other District Activities (Box 1)
    - Luther Hodges - Ethics (Box 1)
    - Substance Abuse Speech Contest (Box 1)
    - International Assembly (Box 1)
    - Nominating Committee (Box 1)
    - RI Notebook for DG (Box 1)
    - International Convention (Box 1)
    - Zone Institute (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Celebrate Rotary Book (Box 1)
    - Proclamation - Wake Commissioners (Box 1)
    - VCP on Eradication of Polio (Box 1)
    - Copies of Rotarian: June 2005-April 2006 (Box 1)
    - Centennial Pins (Box 1)
  - Notebook, General Club visits (Box 2)
  - D 7710 Directories (Box 2)
  - Notebook: Council Meetings, memberships, foundation, etc. (Box 2)
  - Rotary Anniversary Calendar (Box 2)
  - Star Celebrate Rotary, 100 Years (Box 2)
  - Barry Philips, 2007-2008
    - District Council (Box 3)
    - Group Study Exchange (Box 3)
    - Scholars (Box 3)
    - The Rotary Foundation (Box 3)
    - RYLA (Box 3)
    - Interact/Rotaract Clubs (Box 3)
    - Friendship Exchanges (Box 3)
    - District Conference (Box 3)
    - PETS (Box 3)
    - College of Governors (Box 3)
    - D7710 Newsletters/correspondence (Box 3)
    - Rotary Youth Exchange (Box 3)
    - District Awards (Box 3)
    - Membership (Box 3)
    - CART (Box 3)
    - Boys and Girls Home (Box 3)
    - Luther Hodges Ethics (Box 3)
    - Substance Abuse Speech (Box 3)
    - RI International Conference (Box 3)
    - Zone 33-34 Institute (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Disaster Relief (Box 3)
    - Financial Matters (Box 3)
    - Paul Harris Society (Box 3)
    - Polio Plus Challenge (Box 3)
    - Grants and Share (Box 3)
    - District Strategic Plan (Box 3)
    - Duke/UNC Rotary Peace Center (Box 3)
    - Rotary Leadership Institute (Box 3)
    - WASRAG (Water and Sanitation Rotary Action Group) (Box 3)
  - William S. Lefes, 1999-2000
    - District Council, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Summary of Club Visits (Box 4)
    - Assistant District Governors (Box 4)
    - DG Expenditures (Box 4)
    - District Correspondence (Box 4)
    - GSE, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Scholars, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - The Rotary Foundation, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Peace Scholar Program (Box 4)
    - RYLA (Box 4)
    - Interact and Rotaract (Box 4)
    - Friendship Exchange (Box 4)
  - District Conferences (Box 5)
  - District Assemblies (Box 5)
  - PETS (Box 5)
  - College of Governors (Box 5)
  - Newsletters and Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Rotary Youth Exchange (Box 5)
  - District Awards (Box 5)
  - Membership, 2 files (Box 5)
  - CART (Box 5)
  - Boys and Girls Home (Box 5)
  - Centennial Year Activities (Box 5)
  - Other District Activities (Box 5)
  - Luther Hodges - Ethics (Box 5)
  - Substance Abuse Program (Box 5)
  - International Assembly, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 5)
  - RI Notebook for DG (Box 5)
  - RI International Convention (Box 5)
  - Zone Institute (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Rot Found Handbook (Box 6)
  - DG Training Manual (Box 6)
  - Directories for D7720, D7730, D7680 (Box 6)
  - Ethics Program File (Box 6)
  - Governor's Handbook (Box 6)
  - RI Convention-Argentina (Box 6)
  - RI Convention-Calgary (Box 6)
  - RI Convention-Indianapolis (Box 6)
  - RI Convention-Glasgow (Box 6)
  - RI Convention-Singapore (Box 6)
  - RI Convention-Chicago (Box 7)
  - RI Convention Attendees Directory (Box 7)
  - Binder-International Assembly (Box 7)
  - 1999 Catalog National Assembly (Box 7)
  - 1999 Copy of Rotary World (Box 7)
  - 1999 Governor's Handbook (Box 7)
  - 1999 President's Manual (Box 7)
  - D7710 History through 1981 (Box 7)
  - Zone Directories: 1997, 1998, 1999 (Box 7)
  - District Conference Manual (Box 7)
  - President's Manual (Box 7)
  - District 7710 Club Files (Box 8)
  - Tim Mannix, 2006-2007
    - District Council (Box 8)
    - Group Study Exchanges (Box 8)
    - District Conference (Box 8)
    - PETS (Box 8)
    - District Newsletters (Box 8)
- Accession (2009-0225), 2003-2005, 1 Box
  The addition (2009-0225) (450 items, 0.2 lin ft.; dated 2003-2005) includes materials related to district simplified grants.
  - Accession 09/225 (Box 1)
- Accession (2010-0145), 2005-2008, 1 Box
  The addition (2010-0145) (450 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; 2005-2008) includes binders with District Simplified Grant material, as well as materials from the district's committees and activities.
  - Accession 10/145 (Box 1)
- Accession (2012-0078) 1966-1981, 2 boxes
  District histories and Manuals of Procedure, 1966-1981.
  - District histories, including club officers, membership info, and regulations. (Box 1)
  - Manuals of Procedure, 1966-1981 (7 manuals) (Box 2)
- Accession (2013-0060), 1984-2012, 5 boxes
  The addition (2013-0060) ( 7.5 lin. ft.; 1984-2012) includes correspondence, administrative and program files, conference and training manuals, directories, audiovisual materials, and other materials relating to Rotary International's activities between 1984 and 2012.
  - Charlie Hatch (Box 1)
    - Annual Giving, 2002-2009 (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports, 2002-2008 (Box 1)
    - Committee Manuals, 2001-2010 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2010 (Box 1)
    - District Newsletters, 2000-2012, 7 folders (Box 1)
    - District Procedures, 2011 (Box 1)
    - District Simplified Grants, 2003-2007 (Box 1)
    - Donation Information (Box 1)
    - Fact Books, 1997-2011 (Box 1)
    - Future Vision, 2011 (Box 1)
    - GSE in / GSE out, 2006-2009 (Box 1)
    - Major Gifts (Box 1)
    - Paul Harris Society, 2002-2007 (Box 1)
    - Polio, 2002-2007 (Box 1)
    - Rotary Foundation Information, 2005-2011 (Box 1)
    - Rotary Peace Center, 2003-2009 (Box 1)
    - Scholars, 2005-2008 (Box 1)
    - Seminars, 2003-2011, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - ABC Rotary and quiz, 2002 (Box 2)
    - Assorted Pamphlets, 2007-2011 (Box 2)
    - Avenues of Service, 2007-2012 (Box 2)
    - Budgets and Finance, 2003-2011 (Box 2)
    - Cary-Kildare Rotary, 1984-2010 (Box 2)
    - Club Manuals, 2003-2009 (Box 2)
    - College of Governors, 2007-2011 (Box 2)
    - Conferences, 1996-2012 (Box 2)
    - District Directories, 1998-2012 (Box 2)
    - District Nominations, 2002-2012 (Box 2)
    - Event Attendance, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Gleaning Projects, 2010 (Box 2)
    - Governor-Elect, 2003-2004 (Box 2)
    - Inductions and Banquets, 1998-2010 (Box 2)
    - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 2006-2011 (Box 2)
    - Pig Pickin' Events, 1998-2012 (Box 2)
    - Pocket Directories, 1996-2012 (Box 2)
    - Recruitment and Membership, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Rotarians Against Hunger, 2004-2007 (Box 2)
    - Rotary Catalogues, 2005-2011 (Box 2)
    - Rotary Leadership Institute, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Rotary Zones 33-34 Events, 2002-2011 (Box 2)
    - SHARE, 2003-2010 (Box 2)
    - About Rotary International, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Alumni Committee, 1992-2009 (Box 3)
    - Assorted Handbooks (Box 3)
    - Assorted Training Manuals (Box 3)
    - Club Leadership Plan, 2007 (Box 3)
    - Code of Politics, 2002 (Box 3)
    - International Assembly, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 2004-2009 (Box 3)
    - Public Relations, 2000-2007 (Box 3)
    - Report of Action, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Strategic Plan, 2007-2012 (Box 3)
    - World Matching Grants, 2004-2007 (Box 3)
  - Glenn Hood (Box 4)
    - Annual Club Plans, 2005-2006, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Assistant Government Reports, 2005-2006, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - CART, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Chart of Accounts, 1996-1996 (Box 4)
    - Club Dues, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
    - Community Service Chair Reports, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Conferences, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 4)
    - DG's Training Manual (Box 4)
    - District Assemblies, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - District Awards, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - District Council Meetings, 2005 (Box 4)
    - District Council Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
    - District Service Chair Reports, 2005 (Box 4)
    - District Simplified Grants, 2004-2006 (Box 4)
    - DRFC Reports (Box 4)
    - Governor's Banquet, 2005 (Box 4)
    - GSE, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - International Service Chair Reports, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Katrina Relief and Recovery, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Membership, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Newsletters, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Peace Fellows, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - PETS, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Policies, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Presidental Citation, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Rotarian, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Rotary World, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Rotary Youth, 2006 (Box 4)
    - Scholars, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Vocational Service Chair Reports, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Bart Cleary (Box 5)
    - Boys and Girls Homes, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Conferences, 1997-2007 (Box 5)
    - District Awards, 1998 (Box 5)
    - GSE Applications, 1998-2009 (Box 5)
    - GSE Brochures and Handouts, 2001-2010 (Box 5)
    - GSE Budget, 2010 (Box 5)
    - GSE Correspondence, 2008-2010 (Box 5)
    - GSE Inbound, 1996-2002 (Box 5)
    - GSE India Trip, 2009-2010 (Box 5)
    - GSE Travel Expense, 2009-2010 (Box 5)
    - Matching Grants, 1998-1999, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1999-2008 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters, 1998-2003 (Box 5)
    - Rotary Youth Exchange, 2003-2004 (Box 5)
    - Scholars, 1996-1998, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Visting GSE, 1997-2006 (Box 5)
  - Books and Audiovisual Materials (Box 3)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.]
    (6 books, 6 videotapes, 1 floppy disk, 1 tape, 5 dvds, and 23 cds)
- Accession (2015-0145), 2003-2004
  Scope and Contents
  The addition (2015-0145) (1.5 lin. ft.; 2003-2004) includes correspondence, administrative and program files, conference and training manuals, electronic records, and other materials relating to Rotary International's activities in 2003-2004. The bulk of the material relates to Mike Thacker's activities as District General (D-7710).
  - General Information, District General Mike Thatcher (Box 1)
  - District Council, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Group Study Exchange, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Scholars, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - The Rotary Foundation, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - RYLA, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Interact/Rotaract Clubs, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Friendship Exchanges, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - District Conference, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - District Assemblies, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - PETS, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - D7710 Newsletter/Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - District Awards, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - 4-Way Test Activities, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Other District Activities, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Substance Abuse Speech, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - International Assembly, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - RI Notebook for DG, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - PETS President's Manual, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - PETS President's Manual, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - International Assembly, Anaheim, CA, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - International Assembly, Anaheim, CA, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - RI International Conference, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Zone Institute, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Summary of Club Plans, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Visual Aids/ Logos, 2003-2004 (Box 1)